AHMED AL HUSSAIN

E-Mail: ahmadalhosen@hotmaill.com Mobile: +971504254408

PERSONAL INFO

DOB: 22th April Nationality: Syrian, Valid **UAE** Employment visa Language Fluency: English, Arabic

KEY SKILLS

Business Strategy Business Development Retail Banking Operations Client Development Training & Development People Management Communication & Interpersonal Skills.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Degree English literature, Damascus university Civil Engineering institute, Syria

CERTIFICATIONS

- Customer service standard
- Anti-money laundry
- Operation skills
- Role & Responsibilities
- Time managements
- Dealing with impact of Change
- How to Handle A Complaint
- Product & Service Knowledge
- Key Skills Required When **Handling Conflict**
- Pressure & Stress

EXECUTIVE PROFILE

As a result oriented professional offering 16 years' experience in finance & Banking work, customer service, operations and management; I am confident that my qualifications match your organization's current requirements. I am experienced in the banking sector, effectively customer service, operations, I have the ability to work effectively in the highly competitive customer service industry and handle bank products & services. Consistently ensured quality & process compliance, successfully maintained customer's / controlling office's satisfaction, developed business & maximized revenue through relationship management, internal controls, process study and productivity improvements.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Operations / Customer Service

National Bank of Ras Al Khaimah

April 2012 - Present

Achievements:

- Savings deposits, withdrawals
- Issuing negotiable items (cashier's checks, traveler's cheques, money orders)
- Payment collecting
- Promotion of the financial institution's products (loans, mortgages, etc.)
- Business referrals (trust, insurance, lending, etc.)
- Cash advances Resolving customer issues Balancing the vault, cash drawers

Branch Operation Representative:

- Process branch outward Clearing to Central Bank ICCS
- Ensure daily transaction report and vouchers are checked on daily basis
- To provide reconciliation sheets to officer for checking all suspense
- Joint custodian with BOM for cheques and documents
- Generate daily all the mandatory reports pertaining to ICCS

Commercial Bank of Dubai – Islamic Banking, 2008-2010

Handling the input cheques process all the transaction for the customers (deposit and withdrawals) process all the transaction for ATMs

Process all the transaction for exchange foreign currency

Process all the transaction for make Bank draft

Process all the transaction for transfer from account to account

AL Fardan Exchange, Bur Dubai – Head Office (Dubai - UAE) 2006-2008

- Process all the transaction for exchange foreign currency
- process all the transaction for the customers (deposit and withdrawals)
- Data entry for IPO payment.
- Receiving and customers' requirements and complains.
- Test Key department for encoding and decoding payments.
- Telex department for IPO and OPO payment.

Competencies:

- Banking, Finance, Accounting
- Sales & Marketing
- Branch Operations
- Analytical, problem solving skill
- Business development
- Customer Service & Quality Assurance
- Systems/ Process Management
- Controls, Compliances
- Planning and organizing skills
- Relationship management, negotiating skill
- Communication and presentation skills

Customer Service Management:

Provide superior professional sales through how to be seller not teller that exceeds client expectations.

Build and maintain profitable business relations with major clientele and ensure maximum customer satisfaction by achieving best services.

Drive efforts towards developing relationship with existing clients through quality customer service to maintain customer loyalty and business retention.

Ensure that customer requests are attended to and that complaints are handled effectively and promptly.

OTHER SKILLS:

- Huge relation with other bankers in UAE.
- Excellent ability in the process of persuading the client by any products he needs to be marketed, with the ability to control the sale.
- Excellent experience in control of the customers and convince them to products.
- Planning and organizing skills.
- Communication skills
- IFQ certificate (Islamic Financial Qualification) Fluent in MS Office.

PRIOR WORK EXPERIENCE

- Operation (Al mazraa oil field) Syria
- Supervisor, (Al Amir Hotel), Syria
- Customer Service (Al Amir Hotel) Syria

August 2005 – December 2005

August 2004 - August 2005

January 2004 - August 2004